打我，打我…
Hit me! Hit me...
快点，打我，再打，打我…
Hit me, hit me again
求求你打我，再打
C'mon, hit me! As hard as you can
你先喝
You drink this first
不
No!
怕什么？
What're you scared of?
不要，我不喝
No, I won't drink
我先喝一口，你再喝吧
c'mon, I'll have a sip first, then your turn
今天晚上可以有点享受了
Let's enjoy ourselves tonight
讨厌，你这个坏人
I hate you, you're a scoundrel
你怎么搞的！
What's wrong with you?
我，我不是有意的
I didn't mean it
打他，重重的打他
Hit him! Hit him hard
志宏，志宏
Zhihong
又臭又脏，讨厌死了
It's dirty and smells
好了
It's over
拿着    谢谢
-Here you go -Thanks
走开，走开，别阻我做生意
Get lost, I'm running a business here
走…
Beat it
你一天到晚看报纸
You aren't being paid to read the newspaper
赶快干活去
Get to work
志宏
Zhihong
陈志宏，你想拆房子啊
What, you wanna bring the place down?
你神经病，你不要打烂我的东西啊
Are you crazy? Stop breaking my stuff
什么玩儿，他妈的，神经病
What's the matter with you?
这个我帮你包起来
Ill wrap this up for you
秀…秀娟，我…
Xiujuan, I...
谢谢五块钱，不贵的
Five dollars only, it's cheap
包起来
Wrap it up
等一等呀
Please wait
他挺可怜的，到处受人欺负
Poor thing, he gets bullied everywhere!
随便坐
Have a seat
你们请外卖？
You're hiring a delivery man?
老板在后面
The boss is at the back
老板在那里？
The boss is right there
在那
Over there
老板…
Boss
做事要勤快，不能偷懒
You have to be hardworking
不能在街上闲荡
And don't wander around on the streets
早上十点到晚上十一点
10 a.m. to 11p.m.
有一单就要送一单
You'll deliver order by order
一个月四百块
Four hundred dollars a month
店里不包吃不包睡
You don't eat or sleep here
打烂碗碟要赔，你干不干？
And you'll pay for dishes you break, alright?
干，干
Yes, I will take the job
三万    碰
-30,000! -Triple!
喂，你怎么到我这里来呀
Hey, what are you doing here?
哎呀，血，好可怜啊
It's blood, you poor thing
给他们取了蛇胆
They took your gall bladder
就给扔了
And then you got thrown away,
真是的，他们也太残忍啦
it's so cruel
不管你的死活，对不对？
They don't care whether you live or die
不用怕
Don't be scared
好，我给你包扎一下
I'll take care of your wound
我拿点东西给你止血
Let me get something to stop the bleeding
你给人拿了蛇胆，要不把伤口医好
I'll have to attend to the wound...
过不了一个礼拜你就会死了
or else you'll be dead in a week
不要怕呀，我给你缝好
Don't be scared, there'll be stitches
不要怕疼
It won't hurt
好好的休息休息，过几天就会好
Have a good rest, you'll heal in a few days
不要紧，我轻轻的缝，不要怕
Don't worry, I'll be gentle
接好了
It's done
他们这些人，为了迷信蛇胆的功用
They are too cruel, the gall bladder's use...
就把你的胆割了
is exaggerated, they shouldn't have
其实蛇的生命跟人一样宝贵
A snake's life is just as precious as human's
你说是不是？
Do you agree?
你好像听懂我的话对不对？
You seem to understand me
我告诉你，我跟他们不一样
I'm not like them
你放心，乖乖地躺下，盖好
So stay put and have a good rest
好好睡觉呀
Have a good sleep
秀…秀娟，我…我不知道你会来
Xiujuan, I didn't expect to find you here!
原来是你呀，爬得那么快
Oh, it's you! Look at you
伤口好了没有？
Has the wound healed?
呃，快好了吗？
Seem to be doing quite well
只要你听我的话
Just listen to me
再过几天你一定跟以前一样
You'll recover in a couple of days
你爬得那么快
Look at how you're crawling!
我叫你小彪，好不好？
Ill name you Xiaobiao, alright?
好，小彪，乖乖的睡觉吧
Right, Xiaobiao, go to sleep now
你还有什么话想告诉我？
Anything you want to tell me?
我又找到朋友了
I've found another friend
都是给人拿了胆
They all got their gall bladders taken out
你是不是要我帮他们医好？
Do you want me to help them?
好，你的朋友就是我的朋友
No problem, your friends are my friends too
我一定替他们医好，你放心
I'll heal them
不用谢
You're welcome
收工了，你这份工作很好
You're off already? Your job seems to be good
算是长久的了
You've worked there for a while now
自己又没本事
I have no qualifications
做什么全是一样的
All jobs are the same
不过我总算做得下去
But I can keep working at this one
秀娟
Xiujuan
什么事
Yes?
昨天我领了工钱，我想请你看戏
I'd like to take you to a movie
好，午夜场你在翡翠戏院门口等我
How about the midnight show tonight?
晚上见
See you tonight then
有空，再来坐啊
Come again
你们叫的东西来了
Hey, your take-away order is here
对不起
Sorry
死人呀，你什么不长眼睛的！
Damn, couldn't you be a bit more careful?
对不起
Sorry
喂，看什么，有什么好看的
What are you looking at?
没看过？
Haven't you seen a woman before?
看清楚点，你妈妈也是这个样子
Look closer, your mother is similar to me
看呀！你…
Have an eyeful! You...
他妈的！
Damn
看啊！不要钱，赶快看啊
I won't charge, look!
看啊…！
Look!
看啊！
好了，你们不要欺负他了
That's enough, leave him alone
起来
Get up!
钱呢？藏什么去了？
Where did your money go?
说！
Tell us!
把衣服脱了搜
Strip search
他妈的
Damn!
走
Go
秀娟，你爸爸病重就快不行啦
Xiujuan, your father's dying
你快去呀，不然来不及，快点
You better hurry
这里你不要管，快点去吧
Never mind that, c'mon go
这里我帮你收拾
I'll take care of this
开门
Open up
你可回来了，你得赶快想办法
You're back, think of something
死在这可不行哪
He can't just die here
爸爸
Father
你赶快把他送去医院
You've to hurry and send him to the hospital
你看他病成这样子
Look at him
要是他死在这儿
If he dies here...
我房子租不出去了
I can never rent the room out again
那你可要负责啊！
And I'll hold you responsible then
你静一下好不好！
Be quiet
我爸爸不见得会死吗？
My father won't die
哼，你比我还凶呀
You're quite fierce
你赶紧把他弄出去呀
Just hurry and get him out of here
停在街上我可管不着啊
I don't care even if you leave him on the street
秀娟，你可要想办法呀
You'll have to think of something, Xiujuan
这怎么可以呀
I can't do that
我，爸爸
1...Father
三姑，你赶快打电话
Please call the emergency line...
叫救护车来呀
for the ambulance
救护车呀，我去…
The ambulance, alright
秀娟，你可放心吧
Don't worry, Xiujuan
医院会收留你爸爸的
The hospital will take him
他妈的…
Damn
妈的，给我滚，明天不要来了
You're fired, get out of here
我…
A.
我…什么，你看这个打烂了
What? You've broken this
不叫你赔算好的啦
You're lucky you don't have to pay for it
老板，我，我被阿飞抢了
Boss, I got robbed by some hooligans
我看你才是阿飞，滚…
I think you're the hooligan, get lost
排队…
Line up...
两张
Two tickets
只剩一张啦
There's only one left
我要两张
I want two tickets
只剩一张啦
Only one left
我要两张
Two tickets
没有      走开…
-No -Move over
一张
I want one
对不起，客满了
Sorry, it's all sold
两张…
Two tickets...
秀娟，我不早就劝你做舞女
I've been telling you to be a call girl...
你不肯，要是你听了我的话
if only you'd listen
你爸早就好了
It'll fetch you money to cure your father
怎么会死呢？
And then he won't die, will he?
喂，你欠的房租到底给不给
Hey, you still owe the rent
喂，我跟你说话呀，你怎么不理
Hey, I'm talking to you!
房子是你要租的，我不能让你白住
You'll have to pay the rent...
你到底什么时候给呀！
when will you pay it?
她欠你几个月？
How much does she owe you?
一个月
One month's rent
四十元，真不要脸
Forty dollars
老头死了就想赖租
Just because your father's dead
你再不给
You still have to pay the rent or...
我就要报警
I'll call the police
好了好了，拿去吧
Fine, here are the forty dollars
秀娟，你还是跟我走吧
Xiujuan, you better come with me
我带你去见大班，凭你这个样
I'll take you to my boss, you are pretty
那怕没钱赚
You can start earning money right away
你先搬到我那儿去住
For the time being you can stay with me
看你土里土气也不像样
You look like a country pumpkin though
我好好给你打扮，包你会红的
I'll help you to dress up, you'll be popular
怎么样？
What do you think?
你又要跟我说什么？
You want to tell me something?
小彪，你真是我的好朋友
Xiaobiao, you're my pal
你想安慰我是不是
You want to comfort me, right?
你对我真好，你晓得我喜欢的是谁
You're so nice, do you know whom I fancy?
你真的不晓得
You wouldn't know
是对面卖玩具的秀娟
Xiujuan, who sells toys over at the street
今天晚上我约她看戏
Asked her out for a movie tonight
她没有来
She didn't show up
我一气就把她摊子给打坏
I trashed her stand in a rage
是我不好，她这么关心我
It's my fault, she's very nice to me
我对不起她
I shouldn't have done it
你真懂我的心意
You know exactly what's on my mind
我真喜欢跟你做朋友
I love being friends with you
人家都欺负我，只有你们对我好
They all bully me, only you're kind
现在要吃蛇，最好是吃眼镜蛇
This is the best season to savour cobras
阿忠呀
Zhong
来了
Yes, boss
老板叫我什么事？
What can I help you with?
阿忠，你怎么越来越没出息
What's the matter with you?
你怎么偷蛇出去卖？
Are you stealing my snakes and selling them?
老板，我怎么会做这种事情呀
I wouldn't dare do something like that!
赶快去吧
Get to work
这是怎么回事？
What's going on?
笼子也没有坏，蛇怎么会不见？
The cages look okay, what happened?
是不是找小姐？
Are you looking for company?
我要金艳
I want Jin yan
开门，开门
Open up
请坐，阿艳有客人来了
Have a seat. You've a customer, Jin yan
请，谢谢
Please. Thanks
快点，快点脱衣服
Hurry and take your clothes off
怎么啦？
What's with you?
我，我还要来
I want another go
还想玩，那有这么便宜的事
I don't think so
是你不行，我照收钱
It's your problem, I'll charge you anyway
你…
You...
笑话，我又不是不给你玩
Are you kidding? You've had your fun
给钱哪
Pay up now
自己不照照镜子，学人出来玩
Have a look at yourself, what a loser!
喂，起来，这小子又有钱
Hey the boy might have some money
走…
Go...
搜他的身
Search him
搜他身，还揍他一顿
Search him, and beat him up
他妈的，没有用的东西
Damn, you loser
看你敢不敢惹老娘
See if you dare to mess with me now
喔，蛇…
Oh, it's a snake!
救命
Help!
眼镜蛇
A cobra
不要动
Calm down
咬啊，咬啊
Bite him
咬他们…
Bite them all
他妈的，绳子
Damn, it's only a string
谢谢你
Thank you so much
咬死他…
Bite him dead
咬她…
Bite her
咬死她…
Bite her dead
我要更多的蛇，更多的蛇…
I want more snakes, more...
快点
Hurry
他妈的
What the...!
陈志宏
Chen Zhihong
Chen Zhihong...
好大的狗胆
some nerve you've got!
你敢偷老子的蛇，我打死你
How dare you steal from me?
周老板，蛇全都在这里
Please, Mr. Zhou, the snakes are all here
一条也没有少
Not one less
我打死你
I beat you
我还给你，我求求你
I'll return them all to you, please
我求求你
I beg you
周老板，饶我一次
Please forgive me
我下次不敢
I'll never do it again
周老板，饶了我
I beg you
他妈的，还有下次
Damn
我不打死你才怪
rll kill you
他妈的
Damn it
这小鬼，打死你
The brat is peeping, I'll beat you up
救命啊
Help!
那里跑
Where you go?
救命啊
Help!
拿剪刀来把他的剪掉，按住他
Hold him, the scissors
起来
Man, wake up
他像我们喝得那么醉
He drinks like you and me
走吧
Come on
小心
Easy
冤有头，债有主，我没有对不起你
I didn't harm you...
各位观众
Good afternoon
现在报告中午港闻摘要
This is the News at noon
本港昨晚发生一宗离奇恐怖案件
Two victims were found dead in a snake shop...
一间蛇铺老板及一名女子
last night. One of them was the shop's owner,
被发现死在蛇店中
the other was a body of a young woman.
据警方透露
According to the police, it's possible that...
两名死者可能被蛇店内之毒蛇咬死
the deaths were due to venomous snake bites
死者全身呈紫黑色
Their bodies were dark purple in color
据查男死者名周福成
The male victim is identified as Zhou Fucheng
胡先生，你来了
Good afternoon, sir
年约四十岁
Zhou was the owner of the snake shop
是该蛇店老板
He was around forty years old
女死者名张金艳
The dead woman is identified as Zhang Jin yan
二十二岁
Twenty two years old
据闻在附近做舞女为事业
She's a prostitute in the neighbourhood
又据警方证实
According to the police...
前在油麻地庙街后巷中
there are three more bodies...
发现之三名男死者
with snake bites found at the alley...
亦是被毒蛇咬死
behind Temple Street
警方发言人说，命案发生之现场
The police warns that a large number...
走失大批毒蛇
of poisonous snakes have escaped.
呼吁市民特别注意
Citizens are requested to keep a watchful eye
如发现毒蛇踪迹
And report to the police when they spot...
请立即致电报警
the snakes or call the hot line of the...
或通知农林处防止蛇鼠组
Snakes & Pest Control Unit
死鬼，吓死我了
Jeez, you scared the hell out of me!
各位观众现在是潘颖思报告天气
This is the weather report
本港天气继续晴朗
It's a fine day in Hong Kong today
阳光充足
with plenty of sunshine
下午最高气温为摄氏25.1度
The highest temperature is 25.1 degrees
昨晚最低为17.9度
And the lowest is 17.9 degrees
今日上午吹北风，空旷地方…
The winds will be northerly
怎么样，你答应我那罐头货呢？
Where's that virgin you promised?
我答应你的事，怎么敢不办呢
Of course I've got everything prepared
来，我带你去看
Come, I'll show you
芳芳，我实在是受不了啦
Fangfang, I can't stand it
你这里现在先借给我用，怎么样？
Please can I borrow your place now?
不行
No
为什么不行？
Why not?
你答应我的呢？
What did you promise me?
事成了我一定送给你的
You'll have it once the transaction's completed
来，你先穿好衣服出去
Come on and get dressed
半个钟头我就搞定了
Half an hour and I'll be set
我说，今天不行就不行嘛
No, not today
我一定送给你的，为什么不行呢
Why not? You have my word, I'll reward you
时候还没到
It's not time yet
你看，不行吗？
See, won't this do?
你先回去时机成熟
When the time comes...
我就会打电话告诉你的
I'll give you a call
半个钟头…    你先走
Just half an hour... -Now you leave first
你一定要打电话给我
You must call me, okay
蛇是什么时候跑掉的？
When did the snakes disappear?
我也不知道，昨天很多人来卖蛇
Not sure. We had many customers yesterday
我去抓蛇的时候，它们还在笼里头
They were all here
今天早上就不见了
But they're all gone this morning
蛇笼不是关得好好的吗？
Weren't the cages shut properly?
蛇是畜牲，有什么灵性
But after all they're snakes, it's hard to say
老吴，这个人住在蛇铺的隔壁
Old Wu, he lives next door
你昨天晚上有没有听到
Did you hear any strange noises...
蛇铺里有什么特别的声音
coming from the shop last night?
没有，我白天工作很累，睡得很熟
No, I was tired and slept the night through
你要小心点，可能逃了不少蛇
Be careful, there're many escaped snakes
被蛇咬伤了，要进医院，走吧
Go to a hospital if you get bitten
走吧…
Let's go
志宏，昨天晚上我看见了秀娟
Zhihong, I saw Xiujuan last night
你看到秀娟？
Xiujuan?
要不是她叫我
If she wouldn't have called me...
我真的不敢看她
I could not have recognized her
真想不到，秀娟打扮起来那么好看
She looks really pretty when dressed up
真是黄毛丫头十八变，真可惜呀
She's turned into quite a woman; Too bad!
别说了
Stop it
你不舒服呀？
Are you alright?
没什么
I'm fine
看开点，有什么办法
Forget about it
人家有钱就能搂着秀娟跳舞
Those who have money can dance with her
要搂多紧都行
They can hold her as close as they want
秀娟再干下去，总要陪男人睡觉
Sooner or later, she'll become a prostitute
有第一次，就有第二次，谁有钱
If there's a first time, there'll be a second
谁都能玩她
Whoever has money can have a go
不
No
别这样吧
Please stop
你什么都不答应
Why not?
跳舞总不能不跟我跳
You can at least dance with me
胡先生，不要这样嘛
Mr. Hu, please
好了，你答应跟我去消夜
Alright, if you agree to dine out with me...
我就规规矩矩跳
I promise to be a gentleman
最多叫芳芳一起去
We can ask Fang to come along
那你还怕什么？
What else are you scared of?
干杯
Cheers
干，干掉
Bottoms up
再来一杯，最后一杯
Another glass, the last one
不要嘛
Had enough!
不要紧嘛，喝晚了我陪你
Don't worry, I'll be here
好，最后一杯
One last glass
最后一杯
Last one
我跟你喝，干杯    干杯
-rll drink with you, cheers -Cheers
我去一下洗手间就回来
I'm just going to the washroom
芳芳，我看秀娟今天晚上一定行了
Fangfang, it's got to be tonight
借你地方用用怎么样？
Can I borrow your place?
不行
No
有办法，你先出去看看她
Alright, go check on her
我没有醉
ain't drunk
喂，你想带她到那儿去？
Where are you taking her?
讨厌
What a shock!
我的呢？
Hey, where's my reward?
有
Here it is
谢了
Thanks
的士
Taxi
放开我，放开我…
Let go of me
快告诉我
Tell me right now
那砘锇研憔甏到什么地方去？
Where did he take Xiujuan to?
赶快放开我
Let me go
你说
Tell me now
那砘锇研憔甏到那里去了？
Where did he take Xiujuan to?
不关你的事，赶快放开我
It's none of your business
要不我叫了
Let go or I'll scream
他们在那里？
Where are they?
放开我，放开我，赶快放开我
Let go of me
放开我…
Let go
他们在九龙塘爱情别墅
Love Motel in Kowloon Tong;
放开我…
now let go
不要，不要…
No, no, no
打我…
Hit me! Hit me...
求求你，打我…
Please, hit me
你心里不舒服，看开点
Forget about it
有什么办法？
What can you do?
你没钱
You're totally broke
人家有钱就能搂着秀娟跳舞
Those who have money can dance with her
要搂多紧都行
They can hold her as close as they want
我看秀娟再干下去
Sooner or later,
总要陪男人睡觉
she'll become a prostitute
有第一次，就有第二次
If there's a first time, there'll be a second
谁有钱谁就能玩她
Whoever has money can have a go
不，不会的…
No, No, No
秀娟，谁有钱，谁就能玩弄你
Xiujuan, whoever has money can touch you
我看你还是死了好
I think you'd be better off dead
你别怕，死…受不了什么痛苦
Don't worry, it won't hurt a bit
谁都可以玩你，那才活不下去呢
It's better than living as a prostitute
秀娟，你放心，谁糟蹋你
Xiujuan, I promise you
我不会饶过他
I'll take revenge for you
搬家？
Moving away?
小彪，小彪，替秀娟报仇
Xiaobiao, kill for Xiujuan
胡宝春
Hu Baochun
你糟蹋了秀娟，要不是我救了她
You ruined Xiujuan, lucky that I've saved her
她酒醒后会比蛇咬更痛苦
from her despair
你比这些蛇还要毒
You're more wicked than venom
他好像不在
I don't think he's in
再看看
Look again
不用找了，他不在里面
He's not inside
昨天他拿了东西走啦
He took a lot of stuff with him
你是干什么的？
Who are you?
我在蛇铺隔壁开理发店
I'm the hairdresser next door
他可能真的搬走了
He might have really moved
是啊，昨天晚上我真的
Yes, I saw him last night
看见他搬了一大堆东西走了
He took a lot of stuff with him
有什么证据证明他已经搬走了
What evidence have you got that he's moved?
你们跟我来吧
Please come with me
走吧      好
-Let's go -OK
小彪
Xiaobiao
原谅我，我实在不愿意这样做
Please forgive me, I have no choice
我只是不愿意警察抓到你们
I just don't want the police to capture you
虐待你们
And they'll torture you
永别了，我的好朋友
Goodbye, my friends
小彪，你怎么回来了？
Why've you come back, Xiaobiao?
来呀…
Come here
哎呀，你咬我
You bit me
小彪，你咬我，是我
Xiaobiao, you bit me
你身上怎么烧成这个样子了
Look at your burn marks
好可怜呀，小彪，是我不好…
Poor thing, it's my fault...
原谅我吧，来呀…
Forgive me then, come on...
救命啊，救命啊
Help ! Help!